Jonny Shaw

Game Programmer

Jonny Shaw

Dundee, UK

https://jonny-shaw.com jonnyashaw+work@gmail.com

Skills

I am a Game Programmer with experience working both individually and as part of a team; both small and large. I enjoy learning new techniques and software to increase my effectiveness.

I carry out tasks methodically with a particular emphasis on completing them both on time and to a high standard. My main assets are my outgoing nature, willingness to learn and improve my skill set, and my ability to complement an excellent workplace culture. I can adapt to different tasks and projects with experience in other disciplines such as graphic design and 3D art.

I have the following skills and experience in:

- C++
- C#
- Java
- Interface design and implementation
- Unity Engine
- Unreal Engine

Relevant Experience

Professional Masters In Game Development / Programmer

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT, University of Abertay, DUNDEE, UK

I worked with a team of peers to create a game project with constant feedback on professionalism given throughout the duration. In this capacity I worked as the sole programmer for the project and handled implementation of all gameplay features and assets in the Unity engine. All scripts were programmed in C#. I also worked closely with the audio designer to implement Wwise middleware functionality into the project.

For this I have received feedback from tutors describing my professional persona as being 'of great help and assistance to others' as well as being 'typically cheerful' and always conveying a 'diligent outlook'.

Crucial Visual Communications / Digital Artist

NOVEMBER 2014 - JULY 2016, MONTROSE, UK

Shortly after graduating I was offered a position in a small and tight knit creative studio. Very quickly I was responsible for many of my own projects as well as collaborating with colleagues on larger ones. These varied from trade show applications to elevator pitches and physical print installations. I would engage with clients directly to make sure work was completed to the highest standard and on schedule, regularly advising on ways their projects could be developed.

Petrofac Training / Intern Graphic Designer

MAY 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2012, ABERDEEN, UK MAY 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2013, ABERDEEN, UK

During my summer break at University I worked as an intern graphic designer at one of the worlds largest offshore training companies. I worked closely with subject matter experts to update and redesign the visuals for a large number of training materials including classroom presentation, working documents and images. I was asked to return the following summer, based on the good work and professionalism I had exhibited during my first spell.

Royal Bank of Scotland / Private Banking Officer

FEBRUARY 2017 - JUNE 2018, MANCHESTER, UK

Worked as a private banking specialist in the RBS group Manchester office. I helped with day to day banking enquiries as well as chasing up ongoing queries. This included moving large sums of money both domestically and internationally for clients on a regular basis. This role involved helping a number of different clients on a one to one basis. Being personable and having a strong desire to help allowed me to perform consistently well throughout and a key member of the team.

Education

Abertay University / Professional Masters In Game Development

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT, University of Abertay, DUNDEE, UK

Currently studying a professional masters that mimics a typical game studio environment. Mirroring practice and feedback informed by tutors with extensive experience in the games industry and external visits from game studios. I have completed one full game project with feedback from peers describing my involvement as 'highly organised' and the 'ideal work colleague'.

Robert Gordon University / BSc Computing (Graphics And Animation) With Second Class Honours (1st Division)

SEPTEMBER 2010 - MAY 2014, ABERDEEN, UK

In my undergraduate program I had a focus on Computing in the creative arts, studying visual design fundamentals and interfaces, core programming skills in Java and C++ as well as 3D modeling and animation.